A Guide to the Walther F. Goebel papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA162
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence files, 5" Letter
  - Hoving, Thomas P.F. [re] Art lectures at RU, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Howard, C.J., 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - Howard, H.W. [re] Mrs. Otto Westphal, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Hudson, C.S., 1951 (Box 4)
  - Hudson, Floyd E., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Hürlimann, Dr., 1966 (Box 4)
  - Ichihara, Katashi [re] T. Amano, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Idriss, J.M., 1967 (Box 4)
  - Ile De France, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Imperial Chemical Industries Ltd., 1959 (Box 4)
  - Infection and Immunity [re] Goebel review of J-P Dondeau ms, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Ingle, Dwight J., 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Irwin, Donald J. [re] Gertrude Madeja, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Irwin, M.R., 1970 (Box 4)
  - Iserman, A.E., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Jackson L.E., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Jacob, Francois, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Jacobs, Albert C. [re] Paul Méjean, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Jeanloz, Roger W., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Jesaitus, Margeris A., 1949-1968 (Box 4)
    Includes Goebel 1968 recommendation for.
  - John-Brooks, R. St. [re] Goebel "The structure of natural and synthetic antigens" at 1936 July-August London, 2nd International Congress for Microbiology, 1935 July-1936 August (Box 4)
  - Johnson, Ward [re] daughter, Anne, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Jones, L.L. & Co., 1966 (Box 4)
  - Jones, Russell S., 1955-1957 (Box 4)
  - Joó, Istwan [re] contribution to R. Backhausz memorial volume of Goebel and Tsao ms (#117 in Goebel bibliography), 1970-1973 (Box 4)
  - Joseph, M. Mother [re] Emma Anne White, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Jourdian, G.W., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry [re] publication of Goebel ms, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Journal of Experimental Medicine [re] publication of Goebel mss, 1965-1969 (Box 4)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1958-1962 (Box 4)
    Includes Goebel review of 1958 ms by Walton, Rodin, Stammer, Holly and Folkers and 1962 Goebel book review of M. Stacey and S.A. Barker book.
  - Junkin, Joseph Mrs. (Lolo), 1974 (Box 4)
  - Kabat, E.A., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Kac, Marc [re] Goebel election to honorary membership in RU Chapter, Sigma Xi and Kac RU address to Senior Fulbrigh Scholars, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
  - Kanowith, Susan [re] Goebel views on colicines research, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Kapadra, A.R., 1957 (Box 4)
  - Kasai, Nobuhiko, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Katchalski, Ephraim [re] Goebel attending 1964 March Israel symposium on the molecular aspects of immunology (Box 4)
  - Katz, Edward, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Kauffmann, S.F., 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Kawamata, Junichi, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Kawata, H., 1973 (Box 4)
  - Keeler, Isaac, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
  - Kellenberger, Edward, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Kelley, Elizabeth, 1959 (Box 4)
    Includes [re] daughter Anne attending Middlebury College.
  - Kempf, J.E. [re] Kent, Paul W. 1949, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Kimball, Fiske (brother-in-law), 1938-1955 (Box 4)
  - Kirschenbaum, Donald M., 1972 (Box 4)
  - Klenk, Ernst Mrs., 1972 (Box 4)
  - Knott, Alida Mrs., 1964 (Box 4)
  - Knox, K.W., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Kolousek, J., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Kozinski, A.W., 1956 (Box 4)
  - Kramer, Howard D. [re] Lydia Mesrobeanu, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Krim, Mathilde, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Kuhn, Richard, 1955-1962 (Box 4)
    Includes [re] Reinhard Brossmer.
  - Kunkel, Henry [re] W.T.J. Morgan lectures at RU, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Kuroya, Masahiko, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Kuttner, Ann G., 1966 (Box 4)
  - Lackner-Gohari, Jaleh, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Lafaurie, Jacques E., 1971 (Box 4)
  - Laliberte, Henry, 1962 (Box 4)
  - LaMer, Victor K., 1957 (Box 4)
  - Landau, Richard L. [re] Goebel "The Golden Era of Immunology at the Rockefeller Institute" in Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Landy, Maurice [re] 1953 S.A.B. meeting in San Francisco and in 1956 [re] Curtis Williams, 1953-1956 (Box 4)
  - Lanier, E., 1963 (Box 4)
  - Lanson, Francois Mrs. [re] Winifred Watkins, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Lapp, David F., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Leach, J., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Lederberg, Joshua, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Lederer, E. [re] Paris, International Symposium on the Biochemistry of Sugars, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Lee, L. Edgar [re] Chloe Tal, 1965 (Box 4)
  - LeMinor, L., 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Lemkau, Mary M., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Leon, Myron, A., 1955-1959 (Box 4)
  - Lerner, Leonard J. [re] Shuang S. Troy, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Leuthardt, Henry, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Levene, Anna Erickson (Mrs. P.A.T. Levene), 1940 (Box 4)
  - Levin, Louis [re] B. Cowles, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Levis, Dr., 1962 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, Howard B., 1941 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, William H. Jr., 1966 (Box 4)
  - Leyden, Margaret, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Lieberman, Mark, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Liebman, Henry, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Lin, Michael C., 1966 (Box 4)
  - Link, K. (Karl Paul), 1935-1966 (Box 4)
    Includes 1935 handwritten letter (typescript by G. Lewis) and 1958 post card by K. Link.
  - Linton, Mabel Mrs. [re] 2nd Conference on Polysaccharides in Biology, 1956-1959 (Box 4)
  - Lipmann, Fritz [re] Tokumasa Nakamoto, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Lin, Darell, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Livingood, John, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Loeb, Timothy, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - London Company, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Lüderitz, Otto [re] O-antigens, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Luria, S.E., 1945-1964 (Box 4)
  - Lwoff, Andre [re] Royaumont meeting on bacteriophage and Goebel and Jesaitus ms #93 in Goebel bibliography, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Lynch, Wm. R. [re] Avery-Landsteiner award, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
  - Lyons, David [re] art classes at RU in 1972, 1972-1979 (Box 4)
  - McBride, W.D., 1958 (Box 4)
  - McClung, L.S., 1970 (Box 4)
    Includes Goebel biographical sketch and photograph with 2 dachshunds.
  - McClure, M.T., 1947 (Box 4)
  - McGeachie, J. [re] colicine, 1963 (Box 4)
  - McGuire, Johnson [re] Mrs. Goebel (Cornelia), 1947 (Box 4)
  - Mcintosh Laboratory Inc., 1965 (Box 4)
  - McKee, E. [re] St. George Church, N.Y. I, 1942 (Box 4)
  - McKenna, John [re] Scientific journals and Germanic books to Middlebury College, 1968-1974 (Box 4)
  - McLeod, Colin [re] Goebel's election to NAS, 1958 (Box 4)
  - McMaster, Philip R.B., 1959 (Box 4)
  - McNamara, Wm. E., 1969-1971 (Box 4)
  - MacRossie, Wm, Mrs. (Margaret), 1961 (Box 4)
  - Macy, Josiah, Jr. Foundation, 1959 (Box 4)
    Printed agenda and travel instructions, 5th Conf on Polysaccharides in Biology.
  - Magann, George L. [re] trip to Greece, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Mager, J., 1955 (Box 4)
  - Makari, Jack G., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Malo, M.A. Garrido, 1964 (Box 4)
  - [re] Mandelbaum, Ruth, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Mandelstam, Joel, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Manes, Donald Hon. [re] air rights for RU, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Mann, Jacob [re] Chloe Tal, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Marceau, Henri [re] Fiske [Kimball], 1955 (Box 4)
  - Marchessault, Robert H., 1959 (Box 4)
  - Marrack, J.R., 1947 (Box 4)
  - Martel, Paul, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Martin, George [re] purchase of apartment by Dr. Goebel, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Marvel, Carl S. [re] Goebel election to NAS, 1958 (Box 4)
  - [re] Matsushita, Hiroshi, 1958-1962 (Box 4)
    Includes c.v. and photograph of Matsushita.
  - Maxtet, W.R., 1952 (Box 4)
  - Mayer, Hubert 1972 [re] Otto Westphal Mazumder, Pauline M.H. 1974 [re] Avery-Landsteiner Prize to Goebel (Box 4)
  - Mehta, B.M., 1970 (Box 4)
  - Mercedes-Benz Sales Co., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Mercedes-Benz of North America, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Meron, Zwi [re] visit to Israel, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Mesrobeanu, Lydia, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Meyer, Karl F., 1946-1961 (Box 4)
  - Michael, J. Gabriel, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
  - Mikulaszek, E., 1961 (Box 4)
  - Milch, Hedda, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Miller, C. Phillip [re] Goebel's election to NAS in 1958 and Rufus Cole birthday party in 1962, 1946-1961 (Box 4)
  - Miller, Neal [re] Miller's lecture to Senior Fulbright Scholars at RU, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Mink, R. [re] Strasbourg, Réunion d'Immunologie, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Miras, C.J., 1962-1965 (Box 4)
  - Monod, Jacques, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Montreuil Fernand L. [re] Bernadette Dufour, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Moore, Stanford, undated, 1972 (Box 4)
  - Margeris Jesaitis, undated (Box 4)
  - Morell, Pierre [re] Shuang-Shine Tsao, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Morgan, Herbert R. [re] Ronald Hinsdell, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Morgan, Patrick, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Morgan, W.T.J., 1936-1973 (Box 4)
    Includes Morgan Lectures at RU, May 1961 and Morgan notes.
  - Morris, Ann, circa 1960 (Box 4)
  - Morris and Mackenzie, 1957 (Box 4)
    Signed by Cornelia R. Goebel [re] house at Pointe au Pic.
  - Morse, Jane H., 1973 (Box 4)
  - Moser, Hermann [re] Pierre Frédérique, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Mudd, Stuart, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Mueller, George C. [re] Mrs. Goebel, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Mueller, J. Howard, 1949-1952 (Box 4)
  - Mueller, Paul, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Murphy, James S., 1959-1970 (Box 4)
    Includes 1959 September 29 Sigma Xi Executive Committee meeting minutes (carbon copy).
  - Murphy, Samuel G., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Murray, E.G.D., 1942 (Box 4)
  - Nakamura, Keizo, 1961 (Box 5)
  - National Academy of Sciences, Proceedings. [re] publication of mss National Academy of Sciences, Secretary 1968. [re] Tsao presentation of Tsao and Goebel ms at April 1968 NAS meeting. Includes typescript of abstract, 1961-1973 (Box 5)
  - National Institute of Child Health and Development, 1972 (Box 5)
  - National Institutes of Health, 1959 (Box 5)
  - National Instrument Laboratories, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Neter, Erwin [re] Mss reviews for Bacterial Reviews and Journal of Bacteriology, 1964-1969 (Box 5)
  - Neurath, Hans [re] Ms review for Biochemistry, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Neuse, Werner [re] Gift to Middlebury College, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Neville, Harvey A. [re] Honorary membership in RU chapter, Sigma Xi Nevin, F. Reese 1962 [re] Forrest Grimm New York Academy of Sciences 1966, 1962-1971 (Box 5)
  - New York Hospital, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Nomura, M. [re] September 1965, Atlantic City ACS symposium on "Colicines" Northrop, John 1950-70 (Box 5)
  - Nowotny, Alois H. [re] N.Y. Academy of Sciences Endotoxin Symposium in October 1965; Shuang-Shin Tsao, 1963-1968 (Box 5)
    Includes lab manual "Basic exercises in immunochemistry"
  - Noyes, William A. Jr. [re] Goebel election to NAS, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Nungester, W.J., 1967 (Box 5)
  - Nüske, R., 1958 (Box 5)
  - Oberkirehs, Hotel, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Oberndorf, Ludwig, 1948 (Box 5)
  - O'Brien, Paul J., 1958 (Box 5)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development 1945 [re] (Box 5)
  - OSRD contract (Box 5)
  - Olesen, Erling, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Olitzki, A.L. [re] Chloe Tal, 1963-1964 (Box 5)
    Includes Chloe Tal's c.v. and bibliography.
  - Olitsky, Peter K., 1958-1962 (Box 5)
    Includes 1958 handwritten congratulations on Goebel election to NAS
  - Olitsky, Peter Mrs., 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    Includes [re] Plesset's "Noguchi biography"
  - Ørskov, Frits and Ida, 1958-1973 (Box 5)
  - Owens-Illinois, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Oxford University Press [re] Royalties for the Estate of father, Julius Goebel, circa 1940-1962 (Box 5)
  - Packard, Charles [re] Lorraine Gosselin, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Packchanian, A., 1948-1950 (Box 5)
  - Page, Irvine H., 1943-1958 (Box 5)
    Includes tentative program for 1958 May Symposium on connective tissue and atherosclerosis.
  - Paigen, Kenneth [re] Shuang-Shine Tsao, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Painter, Terence J., 1962 (Box 5)
    [see also: Morgan, W.T. in Box 5]
  - Palay, S.L. [re] Shuang S. Troy, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Palmer, Allan, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Pappenheimer, A.M. Jr., circa 1941-1942 (Box 5)
    Includes Pappenheimer et al ms.
  - Parr, H.L., 1938 (Box 5)
  - Parshley, Mary S. [re] Curtis Williams, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Parsons, Charles L. [re] Jordi Folch [Pi], 1945 (Box 5)
  - Paton, R. Townley, 1949 1964 (Box 5)
  - Pattee, Peter A. Mrs., 1960 (Box 5)
  - Patterson, Russel H. [re] Goebel becoming Member at RI, 1944 (Box 5)
  - Paul, John R. [re] Goebel election to NAS, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Pauling, Linus [re] Marie and Fiske Kimball visit to Pasadena in 1947, 1942-1947 (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Paul B. [re] Roger Herriott, 1952-1965 (Box 5)
  - Pelegrina, Ivan [re] Medical care for daughter in Puerto Rico, 1965
  - Pellegrino, Louis, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Penndorf, Paul R., 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Perine, Gordon C., 1954 (Box 5)
  - Perly, E.P. (Box 5)
  - Perspectives in Biology and Medicine [re] Goebel ms "Golden Era of Immunology at the Rockefeller Institute", 1974 (Box 5)
  - Personnel Department (RU), 1972 (Box 5)
  - Peters, John H. [re] George F. Spring, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Petersen, Wm. F., 1941-1943 (Box 5)
  - Peterson, Elbert A., 1957 (Box 5)
  - Petrack, Barbara [re] Marie-Anne Raph, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Petrzelka, Charles, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Pfaffmann, Carl [re] 1966 November RU Conference on Biological and Behavioral Science and 1973 March Pfaffmann address to Senior Fulbright Scholars at RU, 1966-1973 (Box 5)
  - Pfanstiehl, Carl [re] Pfanstiehl Pept, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Pfeiffer, John E., 1939 (Box 5)
  - Pharmacia Fine Chemicals, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Philippon, A., 1966 (Box 5)
  - Phillips, R.A., 1963 (Box 5)
  - Pickels, Edward G. [re] Beckmann (Spinco) instruments, 1959-1961 (Box 5)
  - Pierce Wm. A. Jr., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Pigman, W.W., 1943 (Box 5)
  - Pillemer, Louis [re] Chandler A. Stetson Jr. and Guy T. Barry, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Pollard, Morris, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Pomerat, Gerard R. [re] Tsunehisa Ama [?], 1956 (Box 5)
  - Pope, Arthur W., 1962 (Box 5)
  - Porath, Jerker, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Porteous, Jennifer, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Powell, L.M., 1942-1943 (Box 5)
  - Presbrey, Joseph L. Jr. [re] Goebel Honorary degree from Middlebury College, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Prevost, Gustave, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Price, David E. [re] Elizabeth Miller, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences [re] Mss for publication by Goebel and others in, 1961-1965 (Box 5)
  - Process and Instruments, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Pryde, John, 1933 (Box 5)
  - Puck, Theodore T., 1949-1950 (Box 5)
  - Purves, C.B., 1946 (Box 5)
  - Rajewsky, B. [re] Dr. Weidel, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Randerath, K., 1961 (Box 5)
  - Randall, H.J., 1970 (Box 5)
  - Rands, R.A., 1968 (Box 5)
  - Rank, Rüdinger, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Rapport, M.N. [re] Dr. Tal, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Rauss, K., 1963 (Box 5)
  - Raymond, Jeanette, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Raytheon Co., 1960 (Box 5)
  - [re] Red Tide, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Reeves, Peter, 1963-1970 (Box 5)
  - Reichstein, T., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Reich, Edward [re], 1967 (Box 5)
  - Peter Goldman (Box 5)
  - Reiss, Max, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Reznikoff, Paul, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Ribi, Edgar, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Richardson, H., 1965 (Box 5)
  - Rieber, Manuel, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Rikert, Carroll Jr. [re] Honorary degree from Middlebury College by Goebel, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Riley, Richard F., 1961 (Box 5)
  - Ringuet, Jean, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Rittenberg, D. [re] Goebel election to NAS, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Rittenberg, S.C. [re], 1966 (Box 5)
  - Ronald Hinsdell (Box 5)
  - Rivers, Thomas M. [re], 1958 (Box 5)
  - Reinhard Brossmer (Box 5)
  - Robbins, John B., 1971 (Box 6)
  - Robison, Robert S., 1966 (Box 6)
  - Roblin, Dick, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Rockefeller, David, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Roepke, Martin H., 1958 (Box 6)
  - Roome, Reginald, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Roseman, Saul, 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - Ross, Michael J., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Ross, Mrs. Robert M. (Marsie), 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Rothschich, K.E., 1966 (Box 6)
  - Rous, Peyton [re] Chloe Tal, 1958-1964 (Box 6)
  - Rowley, Derreck, 1964-1967 (Box 6)
  - Roy, Uma Mrs., 1969 (Box 6)
  - Rubin, Alan, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Rubin, Harry, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Rüde, Erwin, 1960-1973 (Box 6)
  - Rudin, Donald O., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Rule, Allyn Mrs., 1963 (Box 6)
  - Russell, Ann T., 1967 (Box 6)
  - Ryan, Francis J. [re] Dr. Matsushita, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Ryan, Henrietta, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Ryan, M.H., 1961-1969 (Box 6)
  - Staub, Anne-Marie, 1952-1972 (Box 6)
    Primarily re Dr. Goebel 1963 May-June visit to Pasteur Institute and collaboration. Includes 1963 February short note by W.F. Goebel to "Dear Otto" [Westphal] on opening of new Max Planck Institute Freiburg, delivered by Anne-Marie Staub.
  - Sabin, Florence R. [re] Elizabeth Miller in 1948; Dr. Sabin's 80th birthday in 1951, 1948-1951 (Box 6)
  - St. Laurent, R., 1958 (Box 6)
  - Salama, Mohamed M., 1964 (Box 6)
  - Sanscartier, J.A. [re] Non-delivered telegram to Mrs. Otto Westphal Santino, Michael 1960, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Santry, Arthur, 1971 (Box 6)
  - [re] Sapelli, Rose, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Sarles, Wm. B. [re] Ronald D. Hinsdill, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Savage, George M., 1960 (Box 6)
  - Schedl, Harold P., 1973 (Box 6)
  - Schleifer, Ann, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Schloesing, J. [re] Clary Schloesing, 1965-1971 (Box 6)
  - Schlossbergblich, Hotel, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Schmid, Karl, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Schmidt, O. Th, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Schoenheyder, F. [re] Margaret Oxholm, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Schofield, Lloyd H., 1965 (Box 6)
  - Schramm, German, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Schultz, Fred W., 1956 (Box 6)
  - Schultz, Julius [re] Pierre Fredericq, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Schwick, H.G., 1968-1973 (Box 6)
    In 1973 [re] Avery-Landsteiner Award, at Strassbourg, Gesellschaft für Immunologie meeting.
  - Science. Mss reviews for publication in, 1965-1970 (Box 6)
  - Scientific American, 1958 (Box 6)
  - Seitz, Frederick, 1969-1977 (Box 6)
    In 1973 [re] Avery-Landsteiner award and Otto Westphal.
  - Sendroy, Julius Jr. [re] Avery-Landsteiner award, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Senkus, Murray, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Seto, Akira, circa 1966 (Box 6)
  - Shaffer, Morris F. [re] election to NAS in 1958, 1956-1958 (Box 6)
  - Shedlovsky, Alexandra, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Shedlovsky, Theodore, 1962 1972-1973 (Box 6)
  - Sheraton Park Hotel, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Sheridan Nurseries, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Shields, A.K. Shockley, Thomas E. 1966, 1955 (Box 6)
    Includes Shockley c.v. and bibliography.
  - Sigma Chemical Co., 1958 (Box 6)
  - Sigma Xi, Society of, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Silber, Gustave, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Silva de John Jr., 1966 (Box 6)
- Administrative subject files
  - Art class, circa 1969-1973 (Box 7)
  - Budgets ca, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - Grant applications, 1959-1971 (Box 7)
  - Grant applications, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - Misfiled Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Grant correspondence, 1961-1974 (Box 8)
  - Student laboratory manual for RI biochemistry course, circa 1956 (Box 8)
  - Scientific notes and manuscripts (Box 8)
  - Chromatography of proteins. Peterson and Sober (Box 8)
  - Colcichin K file, circa 1971 (Box 8)
  - Methylation, 1930 (Box 8)
    [Includes typescript on Purdie Methylation]
  - Phosphorylose [-ase?] [2-p. typescript on preparation and isolation], undated (Box 8)
  - Pneumococcus, 1930s?; [Typescript notes] (Box 8)
  - Pneumococcus Polysaccharide, Type III (Box 8)
    - Structure, 1960s-1970s; Diagrams for slides
- Addendum
  - Manuscripts, 5" Lett (Box 9)
    - M.A. Thesis, U. Illinois, 1921
    - Ph. D. Thesis, U. Illinois, 1923
    - "Derivatives of Camphoronic Acid. "
    - Tsao. and Goebel (#108 in WFG bibliog), 1969
    - Goebel and Tsao (2 folders) (#117 in WFG bibliog), 1972
    - Goebel (#118), 1973
    - Philip Duryee McMaster memoir by Goebel, 1979
    - "The chemical and immunological nature of colocines. ", undated
  - Misfiled correspondence, 5" Hollinger (Box 7)
    - [re] Allfrey, Vincent
    - Al?, T.P., 1950
    - American Chemical Society, 1965
    - [Found with "B"'s] signed "Ruthie", October 24 no year
    - Commings, Comtesse de (Mary), 1974
    - International Congress of Biochemistry, 7th, 1966
    - Ichihara, K. [re] Dr. Amano, 1958
    - Indian Scientific Advisory Board, 1935
      - Appendix to Annual Report of Scientific Advisory Board, I.R.F.A. Report of the ad hoc Bacteriophage Committee of. [re] researches on bacteriophage, 1933-1934; Printed
    - Moore, Stanford, 1972
    - National Science Foundation, 1963
    - Pope, Arthur W., 1962
    - Richtmeyer, Nelson K., 1951
    - Rowley, Derrick [re] Pneumococcus Type C polysaccharide samples prepared by Dr. Goebel ca 30 years ago to R. Derrick, 1967
    - Westphal, Otto, 1961 1969
  - Personal (Box 9)
    - Halstead Estate
    - Mercedes [Typescript entitled "220S" re purchase of car]
    - Wine orders
  - Memorabilia, 2.5" Letter (Box 10)
    - Germanica, 1920s
      - Richard Willstätter. Reprint of 1922 address re Adolf von Baeyer
      - "Here's History of Fine German Book Exhibit" Chicago, 1925 January 10
      - "Ica Minimum-Palmos" German pamphlet on camera apparatus
    - Nature reprint, 1939 January 14
      Mounted on board for making multiple copies, due to large number of reprint requests
    - R.I.M.R. booklets [The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research]
      - Organization and Equipment, 1927
      - Addresses on the occasion of the 25th anniversary of the founding of the Hospital, 1931 May 18
    - Extra reprints of "The Golden Era of Immunology at The Rockefeller Institute", 1975
- "Bernie" to Goebel, partially identified letter, on stationery of Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, Stanford, CA, 1974 January 11 (Box 10)
- The Rockefeller Institute, The Irreverent memoir - An Unpublished typescript by Goebel (Box 10)
- Booklet: "Paul Ehrlich. Begründer der Chemotherapie. Leben-Werk-Vermächtnis" by Heinrich Satter, 1962; 2 volumes Coll. Reprints (Box 10)
  Inscribed to Goebel by Prof. Dr. med. G. Heymann.
  [removed to RAC library 8/9/1988]
- Documents, 1972; oversize flat box (Box 11)
  Award, diplomas, honorary degrees; and 2 oversize folders containing diagrams for 1972 mss and mss drawing and originals; odds and ends.
  - Urbana High School, Urbana, Illinois. High School diploma, 1916 June 9
  - B.A. University of Illinois. Diploma, 1920 June 16
  - M.A. University of Illinois. Diploma, 1921 June 15
  - Ph. D. University of Illinois, Diploma, 1923 June 11
  - Society of Sigma Xi. Membership certificate, 1923 April 18
  - National Academy of Sciences. Membership certificate, 1958 April 29
  - Doctor of Science, Middlebury College, Middlebury, Vermont. Diploma, 1959 June 8
  - RU Faculty and Trustees Certificate on becoming Professor Emeritus, 1970
  - Avery Landsteiner Prize. Certificate of Award, 1973 September 7
  - Rockefeller University Honorary Degree. Diploma, 1978 June
  - Diagrams for 1972 Goebel and Tsao manuscript, oversize folder
  - Manuscript drawings and originals. Odds and Ends, oversize folder
- Laboratory Notebooks
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1949-1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1950-1951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1952-1953 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1956-1957 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1957-1958 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1958-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Laboratory Notebook, T1 Stock History - Goebel, 1949-1952 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory Notebook, Stock Culture - Goebel, 1951-1957 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory Notebook, Rabbit Immunization - Goebel, 1944-1960 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory Notebook, Rabbit Immunization - Goebel, 1960 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory Notebook, Sera - Goebel, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel at Munich, 1923-1924 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Laboratory Notebook - Goebel, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)